He sold his soul for rock n’ roll!
Phantom of the Paradise is a music, comedy, horror
film directed by Brian De Palma.
Singer-songwriter Winslow Leach seeks revenge on the nefarious music producer Swan, who steals both Winslow's
music and his favorite singer for the grand opening of Swan's new rock palace, the Paradise.
Winslow Leach / The Phantom, played by William Finley.
Swan, played by Paul Williams.
Phoenix, played by Jessica Harper.
Philbin, played by George Memmoli.
Beef, played by Gerrit Graham.
The Juicy Fruits / The Beach Bums / The Undeads, played by Archie Hahn.
Phantom of the Paradise is a 1974 American rock musical comedy horror film written and
directed by Brian De Palma, and scored by and starring Paul Williams.
A naïve young singer-songwriter, Winslow Leach (William Finley), is tricked by legendary but
unscrupulous music producer Swan (Williams) into sacrificing his life's work.
In revenge, the songwriter dons a menacing new persona and proceeds to terrorize Swan's new concert
hall, insisting his music be performed by his most adored singer, Phoenix (Jessica Harper).
The plot loosely adapts several classic works: the 16th-century Faust legend, Oscar Wilde's The
Picture of Dorian Gray and Gaston Leroux's 1910 novel The Phantom of the Opera.
The film was a box-office failure and received mixed-to-negative reviews contemporaneously, while
earning praise for its music and receiving Academy Award and Golden Globe nominations.
However, over the years, the film has received much more
positive reviews and has become a cult classic.
The film explores themes of mask, new york city,
rock 'n' roll, suicide attempt, greed.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.